

Giovanni Fernandes da Costa

Senior Software Engineer / Web, Mobile, Game developer / Freelancer

giofcosta@gmail.com

+55 (48) 991216434

www.giofcosta.com



Summary

Software engineer with 15+ years experience, I was able to develop several robust systems with high scalability and work in one of the most important projects that changed the logistic for the largest e-commerce in Latin America as a full-stack developer. Fast and creative thinker, I am focused on solving problems. As a **C# and Javascript specialist,** I am always ready for learn technologies. I am a clean coder and I love to share my knowledge with the people I work with.

Skills

Front-end

Back-end

Desktop

Mobile

DevOps

Software Architecture

Data structures

Game Developer

Design

Languages

Portuguese (Native)

English

Spanish

Fluent
Advanced
Low Intermediary

Keywords

FullStack, Software, Developer, Portuguese, English, Spanish, C++, C#, Java, Go, Javascript, Dart, Front-end, React, Vue, AngularJS, jQuery, Razor, Css, JSS, Less, Sass, Bootstrap, Material-UI, ant Design, MDBootstrap, Ionic, HTML, Telerik, KendoUI, DevExpress, SyncFusion, PrimeFaces, RichFaces, Adobe Flash, Back-end, Asp.Net Web Forms, Asp.Net MVC, Asp.Net Core, JBoss Seam, Java Spring, node.js, Asp Classic, WCF, Desktop, Universal Apps, WPF, VB.Net, Mobile, Flutter, Android, Cordova, Ionic, Xamarin, Windows Phone, Architecture, MVVM, MVC, DDD, TDD, OOP, Design Patterns, Clean Code, Microservices, SOAP, Rest, E-Commerce, UML, DevOps, Infrastructure, Azure DevOps (Visual Studio Online), Windows, Mac, Linux, Docker, Azure, Aws, Google Cloud Platform, JBoss, Apache, IIS, Continuous Integration, GIt, SVN, Mercurial, Source Code, TFS, GitHub, Data Structures, MS Sql Server, Oracle, MySql, Redis, Mongo, Management, Azure DevOps (Visual Studio Online), Trello, Jira, GitHub, ZenHub, MS Project, Excel, Game Developer, Unity 2D/3D, Maya, 3D Studio Max, Design, Photoshop, InDesign, PageMaker, Corel Draw, Illustrator, Personal, Easy to work with, Easy learning, Contributing member, Transparent, Proactive, Easy adaptation, Excellent interpersonal skills.

Experience

After Mercado Livre – Florianópolis, SC - Brazil

2018 - 2019

Senior Software Engineer / **Web, Mobile, Game developer** / **Freelancer:** Available Freelancer, improving my english and technology skills. Development of my first indie game, my website and a mobile application.

Mercado Livre – Florianópolis, SC - Brazil

2017 - 2018

Senior Software Engineer: I Participated in a project as a front-end, developing some components importing some csv information to TMS and Developed the new version of the TMS.

Axado - Florianópolis, SC - Brazil

2016 - 2017

Senior System Analyst: Development and maintenance in a tracking system, making an integration between the site, the desktop services and Zebra and HP printer devices (some IoT skills).

BLACK DRAKE IT SOLUTIONS - Juiz de Fora, MG - Brazil

2014 - 2016

Founder/CEO/CTO: Administration, Development, Design, Game Development, Project Management and Consulting.

Guiando Telecom - Juiz de Fora, MG - Brazil

2013 - 2014

Senior System Analyst: Development and maintenance as outsourced. Our team resolved hundreds of bugs a week in their applications

Nova Consulting - Juiz de Fora, MG - Brazil

2013

Senior System Analyst: Development and maintenance of Java applications.

Affero – Juiz de Fora, MG - Brazil

2012 - 2013

Senior System Analyst: Development and Maintenance of Java applications.

Delage Consulting – Juiz de Fora, MG - Brazil

2011 - 2012

Senior System Analyst: Development and support of a complex Quotation System and start of the remade his Warehouse Software.

Novaprolink Technology – Juiz de Fora, MG - Brazil

2008 – 2011

Senior Developer - Team Leader: Support and development. Development of Company Website, CMS, E-Commerce and a Framework.

Education

Salgado de Oliveira University – System Analyst - Degree - Incomplete	2008
Windows Azure Course – Microsoft/PUC Minas	2011
SCRUM PRACTICAL COURSE – Bridge Consulting/Delage Consulting	2011
OOP Course – Novaprolink Technology/Salgado de Oliveira University	2008
Web Development Course – Salgado de Oliveira University	2008
Basic Computing Course – SOS computers	2002

2011-2012
2017
2018
2018
2010
2017
the largest
d access my